<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-transitional.dtd">
<!--
    # Copyright 2015 WSO2 Inc. (http://wso2.org)
    #
    # Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    # you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    # You may obtain a copy of the License at
    #
    # http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
    #
    # Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    # distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    # WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    # See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    # limitations under the License.
-->
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<head>
<meta content="text/html; charset=ISO-8859-1" http-equiv="content-type" />
<title>Metrics View - User Guide</title>
<link href="../../admin/css/documentation.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all" />
</head>

<body>
    <h1>Metrics View</h1>

    <h2>Introduction</h2>

    <p>
        You can use the Metrics View to see the JVM level and application level metrics in different <strong>charts</strong>.
    </p>

    <h2>Reloading Metrics</h2>

    <p>
        You can use <strong>Reload</strong> button to generate all charts and you can select the <strong>view,
            source and time range</strong>.
    </p>
    <p>
        By default, there are several metric views selected and the charts will be generated using the data from <em>last
            5 minutes</em>.
    </p>

    <h3>Views</h3>

    <p>
        All metric charts are grouped into different <strong>views</strong>. This means that each view can have one or
        more charts. You must select at least one view before reloading all charts.
    </p>

    <h3>Source</h3>

    <p>
        The <strong>source</strong> dropdown shows you a list of metrics sources. The values shown in this dropdown are
        the hostnames of the machines, which reported metrics to the configured database. Even though the machine
        hostname is the default source for the Metrics reporter, the user can specify any meaningful name for the source
        in metrics configuration. In that case, the configured source names will be displayed in this dropdown.
    </p>

    <h3>Time Range</h3>

    <p>
        This is another dropdown to select relative time ranges and set custom time ranges. When you select <strong>Custom</strong>
        from the dropdown, you will see two inputs to enter <strong>From</strong> and <strong>To</strong> values for the
        custom time range.
    </p>

    <h2>Metric Charts</h2>

    <p>
        Metrics charts are <em>multi-line charts</em> and the legend is shown in each chart. You can toggle checkboxes
        shown above the chart to hide/view chart lines. You must select at least one checkbox.
    </p>

    <p>
        The <strong>X axis</strong> denotes the timestamp of metric data and the <strong>Y axis</strong> lines depend on
        each chart type.
    </p>

</body>
</html>

