<!--
 ~ Copyright (c) 2005-2011, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
 ~
 ~ WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
 ~ Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
 ~ in compliance with the License.
 ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ~
 ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ~
 ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 ~ software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 ~ "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 ~ KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 ~ specific language governing permissions and limitations
 ~ under the License.
 -->
<!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN">
<html>
<head>
  <title>Governance Registry Service Metadata Management - User Guide</title>
  <link href="../../admin/css/documentation.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all" />
</head>

<body>
<h1>Governance Registry Profiles</h1>
<h2>Add profiles to Governance Registry</h2>
<p>
WSO2 Governance Registry is providing each user to have their own user profile. User can go to 'My Profile' link
in the main left panel and can fill the default profiles and add some more profiles with different profile names. 
After filling profiles information user can import those profiles as a resource in Governance Registry. User can 
import User profiles as a normal resource in Registry by selecting import custom content media type application/vnd.wso2-profiles+.
This will load a custom UI as follows. 
</p>
<p><img src="images/image1.png" width="492px"/></p>
<p>Figure 1: Custom UI for Profiles</p>
<p>
You have to give the user name of the profiles owner and obviously this user name is the user name of the account owner.
For the future purposes, we are not taking the user name from the session configuration. Once user name submitted all the
profiles information will import to registry as a resource in to "/system/users". This will create a collection inside "/system/users" 
directory with the given user name and inside that there will be a resource called Profiles which contains all the information of 
the profiles of that user.
</p>
<p><img src="images/image2.png" width="492px"/></p>
<p>Figure 2: Updating the Profile</p>
<p>
Successful profile import will direct user to the newly added resource location which will be "/system/users". 
</p> 

<h3> Creating a Custom User Interface</h3>

<p>
In Governance Registry, creating a custom ui is a way for the user to implement his own UI implementatons according to his own wish. It is mainly 
assosiciated with Media types. A detailed sample is available on "How to create a Custom User Interface" under samples folder.
</p>
</body>
</html>
